A Guide to the John Erskine Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8585-c
John Erskine Collection 1898-1941
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8585-c
9 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [1963 Dec 17] 1971 Jan 6
Item Listing
- Manuscript
  - "The Sunbeams", 1898 Apr 19; AMsS, 1 p.
    [Poem written for Cousin Grace.]
- Letters
  - John Erskine to Byron Johnson Rees, 1917 Apr 27; TLS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for reading the essay and calls attention to a misprint; invites him to come to New York to see Columbia University. ]
  - John Erskine to Leo Leonard Twinem, 1921 Nov 21; ALS, 1 p.
    [States that his play,
    Hearts Enduring
    , is published by Duffield & Co., and Duffield is also his business representative; can make royalty arrangements if given more information.]
  - John Erskine to Katherine Lee Bates, 1922 Mar 26; ALS, 2 p.
    [Sends copy of later volume of his poems than the one she used for his introduction; thanks for the delightful visit to Wellesley and to Mrs. Ward for her hospitality; greetings to Sophie Chantal Hart and Vida Dutton Scudder. ]
  - John Erskine to William Griffith, Esq., 1932 Oct 28; TLS, 1 p.
    [Cannot preside as toastmaster at the anniversary dinner (50th anniversary of the Author's Club) since the date was changed from Nov 10 to Nov 9 because he is giving a lecture at Columbia University that day.]
  - John Erskine to William Griffith, 1932 Nov 2; TLS, 1 p.
    [ James Howard Bridge visited him about suggestions for toastmastership of the Author's Club anniversary dinner but he will not be able to attend the dinner]
  - John Erskine to John Stuart Groves, 1940 Feb 19; TPCS
    [Consents to autograph his book,
    The Moral Obligation
    . ]
  - John Erskine to John Stuart Groves, 1940 Feb 24; TLS, 1 p.
    [Returns
    with annotation and autograph; considers this his first book and dates his reputation from it, even though it is listed as tenth in
    Who's Who
    , "since it is the first book in which I expressed myself."]
  - John Erskine to Gay, 1941 Dec 16; TLS, 1 p.
    [Expresses gratitude for kindness during visit; was pleased to see Mrs. Beaman; is proud that (Henry) Lee Shippey mentioned him in his column.]